Inventory of the Michael Blinov collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Michael Blinov collection
1826-1985
2003C39
Blinov, Michael, collector.
19 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (8.0 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Memoirs, other writings, correspondence, personal documents, bulletins, newsletters, printed matter, and photographs, relating to Russian military history, especially during World War I and the Russian Civil War, and to Russian émigré affairs. Includes papers of individual émigrés and records of émigré veterans' organizations.
Administrative Information
Access
Microfilm use only.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2003.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Michael (Mikhail) Blinov received the material in his collection from major émigré organizations in California: the Society of the Russian Veterans of World War I, Los Angeles, the Society of the Russian Veterans of World War I, Inc. (San Francisco) and the San Francisco division of the Russian All-Military Union (Russkii obshchevoinskii soiuz - ROVS).
These veterans' organizations, in addition to their organizational records, preserved memoirs, other writings, correspondence, personal documents, bulletins, newsletters, printed matter, and photographs, relating to Russian military history, especially during World War I and the Russian Civil War, and to Russian émigré affairs, created by smaller or subordinate émigré organizations and individual émigrés. Among those, materials donated by Leonid Krivosheev are of high historical value. He was the director of the Museum of the Leib-Gvardii Volynskii polk (regiment), and in that capacity he collected materials on the regiment's history going as far back as the 1860s.
Research files for the "Dom Romanovykh" (House of the Romanovs) reference book are also of extreme interest, because they contain documents and illustrations relating to the Russian royal family.
A number of memoirs describe episodes and events of World War 1, the 1917 February and October revolutions and Civil War in Russia. The collection includes illustrations and photographs reflecting the everyday life of Russian troops at Gallipoli and émigré life in various countries.
The collection is divided into two major groups according to the organizations that collected the documents: the Society of the Russian Veterans of World War I, Los Angeles and the Society of the Russian Veterans of World War I, Inc. (San Francisco); and into two smaller groups according to individual collectors. Within these groups the material was arranged following the original order of the documents.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
World War, 1914-1918--Russia.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Russia--Emigration and immigration.; Russia--History, Military.
Related Collections
Vrangel' Collection, 1916-1929, Hoover Institution Archives
Mariia Dmitrievna Vrangel' Collection, 1915-1944, Hoover Institution Archives
Vooruzhennye Sily na IUgie Rossii. Nachal'nik snabzheniia Records, 1916-1926, Hoover Institution Archives
Vooruzhennye Sily na IUgie Rossii. Sudnoe otdielenie. Records, 1918-1927, Hoover Institution Archives
Alexandre Georgievich Tarsaidze Papers, 1648-1977, Hoover Institution Archives
Collection Contents
- Microfilm Reel List
  - Reel 1 = Box/Folder 1.1 - 1.38
  - Reel 2 = Box/Folder 2.1 - 2.12
  - Reel 3 = Box/Folder 2.13 - 3.4
  - Reel 4 = Box/Folder 3.5 - 4.1
  - Reel 5 = Box/Folder 4.2 - 4.20
  - Reel 6 = Box/Folder 5.1 - 5.15
  - Reel 7 = Box/Folder 5.16 - 6.7
  - Reel 8 = Box/Folder 6.8 - 7.3
  - Reel 9 = Box/Folder 7.4 - 8.1
  - Reel 10 = Box/Folder 8.2 - 8.9
  - Reel 11 = Box/Folder 8.10 - 9.5
  - Reel 12 = Box/Folder 9.6 - 10.6
  - Reel 13 = Box/Folder 10.7 - 11.1
  - Reel 14 = Box/Folder 11.2 - 12.1
  - Reel 15 = Box/Folder 12.2 - 12.15
  - Reel 16 = Box/Folder 13.1 - 13.14
  - Reel 17 = Box/Folder 13.15 - 14.12
  - Reel 18 = Box/Folder 14.13 - 15.4
  - Reel 19 = Box/Folder 15.5 - 15.8
  - Reel 20 = Box/Folder 15.9 - 16.2
  - Reel 21 = Box/Folder 16.3 - 16.16
  - Reel 22 = Box/Folder 17.1 - 17.5
  - Reel 23 = Box/Folder 17.6 - 18.1
  - Reel 24 = Box/Folder 18.2 - 19.8
  - Reel 25 = Box/Folder 19.9 - 20.5
- Society of the Russian Veterans of World War I, Los Angeles, 1935-1980 (Box 1-2)
  Includes files of various émigré organizations and individuals in original order
  - Nekliutin, Dmitrii Matveevich, President (Chairman) of the Society, correspondence with various organizations and individuals, 1941-1980
    - United States Congress, 1950 (Folder 1: 1)
    - United States Senate, 1950 (Folder 1: 2)
    - International Refugee Organization. United States Office, 1950 (Folder 1: 3)
    - California. Governor's Office, 1950 (Folder 1: 4)
    - Committee of United Russian Christian Organizations of Los Angeles for Aid to Displaced Persons, 1950 (Folder 1: 5)
    - Federation of Russian Charitable Organizations of the United States, San Francisco, 1951 (Folder 1: 6)
    - Order of Former Russian Military, Inc., 1955-1956 (Folder 1: 7)
    - Various veteran organizations outside Russia, 1948-1971 (Folder 1: 8)
    - Society of the Russian Veterans of the World War, Inc., San Francisco (Puchkov, F., and others), 1946-1980 (Folder 1: 9-11)
  - Kaiut-Kompaniia (Los Angeles) files, 1935-1961
    - Krylov, A. N., book reviews, undated (Folder 1: 12)
    - Krasovskii, D. M., 1935-1961
      Includes typescripts of articles, book and press reviews, critivcal essays, and translations
      - "Sergei Sergeeviich Prokof'ev", undated (Folder 1: 13)
      - "Biblioteka Pushkina", undated (Folder 1: 14)
      - "Sevastopol'", undated (Folder 1: 15)
      - "Admiral Spiridov", undated (Folder 1: 16)
      - "Amerikantsy dolzhny znat' pravdu o sotsialisticheskikh stranakh", 1961 (Folder 1: 17)
      - "Grammatika Ivana Fedorova", 1955 (Folder 1: 18)
      - "Pervaia voenno-morskaia shkola v Rossii", 1955 (Folder 1: 19)
      - "Razgovory iz dvuch uglov", 1943 (Folder 1: 20)
      - "Grazhdanskaia azbuka i ukaz Petra Velikogo", 1958 (Folder 1: 21)
      - "Hoover War Library", undated (Folder 1: 22)
      - "Istoriia i sovistoriki", undated (Folder 1: 23)
      - Review of Moi vospominaniia by A.N.Krylov, 1945 (Folder 1: 24)
      - "Russkiie geograficheskiie nazvaniia v Amerike", undated (Folder 1: 25)
      - "Guademaus Igitur!", 1958 (Folder 1: 26)
      - "Razvenchannyi Stalin", undated (Folder 1: 27)
      - "Atomnyi korabl'Lenin", 1957 (Folder 1: 28)
      - "Polozhitel'nye geroi sovetskogo romana", 1957 (Folder 1: 29)
      - "Vozrozhdenie russkogo flota posle Krymskoi voiny", undated (Folder 1: 30)
      - "Frantsiia i anglo-germanskii morskoi dogovor", 1935 (Folder 1: 31)
        Translation of excerpts from the article "France and Anglo-German Naval Treaty" by André Géraud
      - "Deklaratsiia prav narodov Rossii", undated (Folder 1: 32)
      - "Flot v tsarstvovaniie imperatorov Aleksandra II i Aleksandra III", undated (Folder 1: 33)
    - Unidentified authors
      - "Zadachi budushchei Rossii", undated (Folder 1: 34)
      - "Vospominaniia o grazhdanskoi voine na Kaspiiskom more", 1950 (Folder 1: 35)
      - "Atomnyi flot", 1956 (Folder 1: 36)
      - "200-letie morskogo kadetskogo korpusa", undated (Folder 1: 37)
      - Untitled typescript describing 1918 events in Sevastopol', undated (Folder 1: 38)
  - Writings, notebooks, and newspaper clippings, 1930-1970 (Folder 2: 1-2)
  - Kaliforniiskii otdel Soiuza pervopokhodnikov - uchastnikov 1-go Kubanskogo generala Kornilova pokhoda, statement and minutes of board meetings, 1951-1969 (Folder 2: 3)
  - Skorodumoff, Michael F., correspondence and a leaflet, 1953-1959 (Folder 2: 4)
  - Obshchestvo gallipoliitsev v Los-Anzhelese, 1946-1959 (Folder 2: 5-6)
    Includes correspondence of Boris Esipov and Almanac Gallipoli
- Society of the Russian Veterans of World War I, Inc., and Russian All-Military Union, San Francisco, 1869-1984 (Box 2-16, 20)
  - Budberg, Aleksei Pavlovich
    - Service record, undated (Folder 2: 7)
      Includes list of Vladivostok fortress personnel
    - Correspondence, 1931-1935 (Folder 2: 8-10)
    - Writings
      - "Iz vospominanii o proshlom (1879-1886)," manuscript, undated (Folder 20: 1)
      - "Raznye zametki o Sibirskoi armii," manuscript, undated (Folder 20: 2)
      - "Sibirskie vospominaniia (1895-1904)," manuscript, undated (Folder 2: 11-14)
  - Petrov, Pavel Petrovich, 1953-1968 (Folder 3: 1)
    Includes documents relating to the Order of Former Russian Military, Inc., Russian All Military Union, and letters from V. K. Vitkovskii
  - Petrovsky, Vladimir Alekseevich, personal papers, 1950-1969 (Folder 3: 2-3)
  - Poliakoff, Simon K., personal papers, 1976-1977 (Folder 3: 4)
  - Flug, Vasilii. "Vospominaniia o generale Budberge," manuscript, undated (Folder 3: 5)
  - Kambalin, A. I. "Tretii Barnaul'skii sibirskiii polk v ledianom pokhode," manuscript, undated (Folder 3: 6-8)
  - Konevega, Vladimir Iosifovich, personal papers, 1912-1932 (Folder 3: 9)
  - Kremer, Serge, personal papers, 1957-1959 (Folder 3: 10)
  - Popov, Boris Ivanovich, Chairman of the Society of the Russian Veterans of World War, Inc., San Francisco
    - Correspondence, 1954-1970
      - Various societies of Russian veterans and individual veterans, 1957-1970 (Folder 3: 11-12)
      - Komitet pomoshchi russkim voennym invalidam za rubezhom, San Francisko, 1954-1969 (Folder 3: 13)
    - Photo album, undated (Folder 20: 3)
    - Russkie voennye organizatsii v San Frantsiscko, announcements and appeals, 1962-1970 (Folder 4: 1)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1962-1967 (Folder 4: 2)
    - Speech presented at a meeting commemorating Nicholas II, Emperor of Russia, 1959 (Folder 4: 3)
    - Boris F. Bulatsel file, 1932-1967 (Folder 4: 4)
      Includes two letters (copies) addressed to General IA. F. Shkinskii
    - Materials relating to the reign and life of Nikolai II, 1957-1959 (Folder 4: 5)
  - Puchkov, Fedor Abramovich, Chairman of the Russian All Military Union in America (ROVS), San Francisco, 1919-1953
    - Correspondence
      - Arkhangel'skii, Aleksei Petrovich, 1952-1953 (Folder 4: 6)
      - Esipov, Boris, 1951 (Folder 4: 7)
      - Lampe, A. A., 1951 (Folder 4: 8)
      - Lavrov, A., 1951 (Folder 4: 9)
      - Nekliutin, Dmitrii Matveevich, 1951-1952 (Folder 4: 10)
      - Osipov, Alex, 1951 (Folder 4: 11)
      - Riasnianskii, Sergei Nikolaevich, 1950-1952 (Folder 4: 12)
      - Vitkovskii, V. K., 1950-1952 (Folder 4: 13)
      - Russian émigré military societies, 1950 (Folder 4: 14)
    - Speeches and writings
      - "Vos'maia kamskaia diviziia v sibirskom ledianom pokhode," manuscript and printed version, undated (Folder 4: 15-16)
      - "Khabarovskii pokhod," manuscript, undated (Folder 4: 17-18)
      - "K desiatiletiiu Khabarovskogo pokhoda," manuscript, 1931 (Folder 4: 19)
      - "Krushenie Semenovskogo 'fronta'," manuscript, undated (Folder 4: 20)
      - "Prichiny porazhenia Germanii vo Vtoroi mirovoi voine," manuscript, undated (Folder 5: 1)
      - "Russkii natsional'nyi vopros i innostrantsy" typescript, undated (Folder 5: 2)
      - " Mart 1952 goda: Iz zhizni Russkogo obschche-voinskogo soiuza i nashego obschchestva," typescript (Folder 5: 3)
      - "Uroki voiny v Koree, " typescript, undated (Folder 5: 4)
      - "Atomnaia bomba na pole srazheniia," typescript, undated (Folder 5: 5)
      - Operations of the White Army during the Civil War, reports, orders, and day books, 1919-1922 (Folder 5: 6)
  - Reshetnikov, Dimitrii Ionovitch
    Writings
    - "Velikii Sibirskii ledianoi pokhod," manuscript, part 4, undated (Folder 5: 7-9)
    - "Velikii Sibirskii ledianoi pokhod," typescript and printed version, undated (Folder 5: 10)
  - Sartori, Nikolai Petrovich, personal papers, 1921-1931 (Folder 5: 11)
  - World War I and World War II maps (hand-drawn), undated (Folder 5: 12)
    Includes newspaper clippings
  - Fond spaseniia rodiny imeni Velikogo Kniazia Nikolaia Nikolaevicha
    - Budberg, Aleksei Pavlovich, 1930-1932 (Folder 5: 13)
      Contains correspondence including letters from General E. K. Miller
    - Nekhoroshev, V. I., 1931-1935 (Folder 5: 14-15)
      Includes reports to Russian All-Military Union (ROVS), appeals, and financial documents
    - Financial documents, 1930-1932 (Folder 5: 16-17; 6 :1-2)
      Includes reports by treasurer, V. I. Nekhoroshev, and letters from generals P. N. Krasnov and V. M. Molchanov
  - Commemoration of the 50th anniversary of the Russian revolution by Russian military organizations in San-Francisco, 1967 (Folder 6: 3)
    Includes financial documents, correspondence, and clippings
  - Consolidated Committee of the Russian National Organizations in San Francisco, 1949-1950 (Folder 6: 4)
    Includes materials relating to the Sr.Vladimir Home for the Aged and correspondence realating to aid to Russian displaced persons
  - Damskii kruzhok Obshchestva russkikh veteranov Velikoi voiny, 1930-1932 (Folder 6: 5)
    Contains correspondence, reports, flyers, and clippings
  - Vestnik raionnogo pravleniia Obshchestva russkikh ofitserov General'nogo shtaba i Central'nogo pravleniia Obshchestva russkikh ofitserov v Korolevstve serbov, khorvatov, i sloventsev (Yugoslavia), 1928-1939 (Folder 6: 6)
  - Russian All-Military Union (ROVS) orders, postcards, and clippings, 1937-1970 (Folder 6: 7)
  - Vremennoe pravitel'stvo Dal'nego Vostoka and Kantseliariia vdovstvuiushchei imperatritsy Marii Fedorovny, 1919-1928 (Folder 6: 8)
    Includes typescript "Organizatdionnye puti zarubezhnogo russkogo osvoboditel'nogo dvizhenia" and letter from Count de Marter to the High Commissioner of France in Omsk
  - Vestnik Obshchestva russkikh veteranov velikoi voiny
    - Puchkov, Fedor Abramovich, correspondence
      - Correspondence
        - Filimonov, Boris B., 1949-1952 (Folder 6: 9)
          Includes his writings for Vestnik (manuscripts) and subscription requests
        - Matsylev, Sergei Aleksandrovich, 1952 (Folder 6: 10)
        - Woinarsky, Boris, 1952 (Folder 6: 11)
    - Editorial files
      - Issue of Vestnik, undated (Folder 6: 12-13)
      - Articles, essays, memoirs, and notes, 1959-1961 (Folder 6: 14; 7: 1-2)
      - Manuscripts and typescripts relating to issues nos. 192, 197, and 198, 1944-1952 (Folder 7: 3-8)
      - Common Council for American Unity, press releases, 1953-1954 (Folder 7: 9)
    - "Who's Who of Officers in the Russian Army, Navy, and Air Force in World War, 1939-1945", undated (Folder 7: 10)
      Includes invitation to the 1942 annual meeting, with a list of invitees
    - Articles, notes, and poetry, undated (Folder 7: 11)
  - Shtandart, organ nezavisimoi legitimno-monarkhicheskoi mysli, no. 91, 1969 (Folder 7: 12)
  - Krivosheev, Leonid Andreevich, Director of the Museum of the Leib-Gvardii Volynskii regiment
    - Kalis Funeral Home memorial book, 1971 (Folder 7: 13)
    - Personal correspondence, 1970-1976 (Folder 8: 1-2)
    - Pokrovskii, Grigorii Vasil'evich, correspondence, obituaries, and clippings, 1961-1969 (Folder 8: 3)
    - Leib-Gvardeiskii Volynskii polk, 1877-1969 (Folder 8: 4-5)
      Includes correspondence, financial documents, writings, leaflets, and questionnaires
    - "Dom Romanovykh" reference book, 1958-1965 (Folder 8: 6)
      Contains research files including clippings and pages from Final v Kitae by Petr Balakshin.
    - Russian revolution and Russian military émigrés' life in Yugoslavia, 1917-1969 (Folder 8: 7)
      Includes clippings and photographs depicting military maneuvers and parades of the Russian army
    - The Romanov royal family, 1956-1970 (Folder 8: 8-10)
      Includes reports on discipline violation by officers
    - Association des Officiers des Anciens Régiments de la Garde Impériale, Paris
      - Correspondence, 1935-1966 (Folder 9: 1-2)
        Includes announcements, minutes of the association and Vestnik Gvardeiskogo ob'edineniia, no. 7.
      - Adamovich, Ivan Nikolaevich, minutes of the Association, announcements, and financial documents, 1936-1966 (Folder 9: 3-6)
      - Gering, Aleksei Alekseevich, 1926-1975 (Folder 9: 7)
        Includes correspondence and editorial files, mostly memoirs, for the Voennaia byl' magazine
      - Koulitzky, Alexandre de, Commandant de l'Ordre de Pierre le Grand en Belgique, 1930-1936 (Folder 9: 8)
        Includes correspondence relating to the Ob'edinenie russkikh ofitserov, uvechnykh i invalidov Velikoi voiny
      - Tatishhchev, Dmitrii Sergeevich, 1876-1975 (Folder 9: 9)
        Contains correspondence relating to the Soiuz Leib-Gvardii Tsarskosel'skikh strelkov, two letters to Duke Andrei Vladimirovich, clippings, and printed matter
      - Chenkeli, Akakii Ivanovich, 1929-1930 (Folder 9: 10)
        Includes correspondence with Aristide Briand, Minister of Foreign Affairs of France, and a letter from N. Tokhadze
      - Vakhvakhova, Mariia Nikolaevna, Duchess, correspondence, 1877-1878 (Folder 9: 11)
    - Neelov, N. L.
      - Writings
        - Bezstrashnyi vit'az' imperatorskoi Rossii, geroi voiny i emigratsii, General Michail Fedorovich Skorodumov, pamphlet, undated (Folder 9: 12)
        - Moi otvet polkovniku Rogozhinu typescript, undated (Folder 10: 1)
      - Printed matter
        - Bulleten' Obedinenia Leib-Gvardii Moskovskogo polka, nos. 79-80, 85, 87, 1939-1941 (Folder 10: 2)
        - Chasovoi, nos. 69-70, 1931 (Folder 10: 3)
        - Nashi vesti, nos. 270-271, 1968-1969 (Folder 10: 4)
      - Predstavlenie chinov rossiiskoi imperatorskoi gvardii ego imperatorskomu vysochestvu velikomy kniaziu Vladimiru Kirillovichu v g. Parizhe, 1938 (Folder 10: 5)
      - Obiedinenie Leib Gvardii pervogo ego velichestva strelkovogo polka, correspondence, financial papers, and greeting forms, 1941-1957 (Folder 10: 6)
      - Dubenskii, Dmitrii Nikolaevich, memoirs, 1921 (Folder 10: 7-8)
      - Korostovets, Izmail Vladimirovich and Maria Karlovna, identification documents, mostly passports, 1907-1927 (Folder 10: 9-10)
      - Kraevaia Rada and the White Army in the south of Russia, 1918-1919 (Folder 10: 11)
        Contains report from the delegation of Kubanskaia rada to Paris and a letter to N. S. Riabovol from I. L. Makarenko
      - Severo-Zapadnaia armiia and Komanduiushchii vooruzhennymi silami iuga Rossii, military orders and correspondence, 1919-1920 (Folder 10: 12)
      - Miller, Evgenii Karlovich, 1919 (Folder 10: 13)
        Includes letter to General N. N. Iudenich regarding the situation with the North Western army
      - Ustav o voinskoi discipline, 1923-1924 (Folder 10: 14)
        Includes a circular and correspondence
      - Documents relating to the situation in Azerbaijan, 1919 (Folder 10: 15)
      - "Vospominaniie o russkom voprose v slavianskikh zemliakh" typescript, 1920 January 17 (Folder 10: 16)
      - Yudenich, Nikolai Nikolaevich, 1927 November 22 (Folder 10: 17)
        Includes letter to Evgenii Karlovich Miller
      - Notebook, undated (Folder 10: 18)
    - Dolgorukov family, album of illustrations, undated (Folder 10: 19)
    - Family of Nicholas I, Emperor of Russia, album of photographs, undated (Folder 11: 1)
    - History of the Volynskii regiment and individual officers, 1877-1914 (Folder 11: 2)
      Includes orders, reports, instructions, food supply list, and correspondence
      - Russo-Turkish War
        - Newspapers, 1877-1878 (Folder 11: 3)
          Includes newspapers Russkii invalid, Golos, Letuchii voennyi listok, and Varshavskii dnevnik
        - 50th anniversary of the battle at Tashkisen (Bulgaria) file, 1927 (Folder 11: 4-5)
          Contains memoirs and other information about the battle, correspondence, photographs, newspaper clippings, and a list of officers of the Volynskii regiment
        - 50th anniversary of the Russo-Turkish War, 1927-1933 (Folder 11: 6-7)
          Includes pamphlet, newspapers (mostly Bulgarian), sheet music, posters, and clippings
        - Photographs, postcards, and book illustrations, undated (Folder 11: 8-10)
      - World War I
        - Battle at Lodz, 1932-1933 (Folder 11: 11)
          Contains maps and articles by G. Petrichenko, G. Saks, and Nikola L. Pavlič
        - "Smorgon'-Krevoo-Zales'ie" itinerary, 1931 (Folder 11: 12)
        - Photographs and watercolors depicting the city of Smorgon' (Vilna), undated (Folder 11: 13)
      - Assault on the 2nd battalion of the Volynskii regiment, 1907-1933 (Folder 12: 1)
        Contains Niva magazine no. 29, 1907, regiment's envelopes, and 1933 newspaper clippings
      - Leib-Gvardii Volynskii, Finliandskii, Pervyi Grenaderskii, and other regiments, 1931-1976 (Folder 12: 2-3)
        Contains newspaper and magazine clippings and other illustrations, mostly relating to the Russo-Japanese war, 1904-1905
      - Memoirs and reports, 1931-1939 (Folder 12: 4-9)
        Contains manuscripts and typescripts by colonels Kolokolov, Evert, Gershel'man, V. Olsuf'ev, Viskovskii; Generals A. Gerua and A. Galkin, Sub-Lieutenant M. A. Meder; Captain M. Terletskii, and others; translation of a Polish article relating to General Dmitrii Komarov
      - Correspondence, court minutes, clippings relating to the Court of Honor investigation of allegations against General A. L. Nosovich, 1955-1958 (Folder 12: 10)
      - Correspondence, poetry, and data relating to the history of the Volynskii regiment, 1935-1962 (Folder 12: 11)
      - Mikhailov, A. M. writings, 1932
      - Khivinskoe khanstvo manuscript, 1932 (Folder 12: 12)
      - Khivinskaia ekspeditisiia, manuscript and map of Khiva, 1932 (Folder 12: 13)
      - 100th anniversary of the Russian-Polish War, newspaper clippings, drawings, and photographs, 1931 (Folder 12: 14-15)
      - Krivosheev, L. A., transcript of speech on the battle of the Volynskii regiment at Ponarskie heights, Poland, with illustrations, 1931 (Folder 13: 1-4)
        Includes the poem Ponarskie vysoty by V. A. Artamonov and a letter from General Gerua to General A. P. Balk
    - Commemorative event in memory of Alexander I, Emperor of Russia, in Warsaw, 1960 (Folder 13: 5)
      Includes description of the ceremony copied by hand from a French publication (publihsed in 1929 in Warsaw)
    - Grand Duke Nikolai Konstantinovich, 1960-1966 (Folder 13: 6)
      Contains newspaper clippings, typescripts, and three prints depicting Grand Duke Nikolai Konstantinovich
    - Russian revolution, 1917-1931 (Folder 13: 7)
      Includes correspondence of General V. I. Visokovskii, memoirs, diaries of Captain Cherniaev
    - Abdication manifesto of Nicholas II, Emperor of Russia, newspaper clipping, 1917 (Folder 13: 8)
    - Abdication manifesto of Grand Duke Mikhail, newspaper clipping, 1917 (Folder 20: 4)
    - "Poslednie piat' dnei tsarskogo Petrograda (23-28 fevralia 1917)," diary of the last mayor of Petrograd, manuscript, ">1922 (Folder 13: 9-10)
    - Skobelev M. D., General, postcards with views of Borodino and newspaper clippings, 1914-1936 (Folder 13: 11)
    - Molitvennyi ugol pamiati Leib-Gvardii Finlandskogo polka, bulletin, 1972 (Folder 13: 12)
    - "Akafist sviatiteliu Spiridonu," manuscript and typescript, 1911 (Folder 13: 13)
    - Zhitie Sviatitelia Spiridona, booklet and cover letter, 1927 (Folder 13: 14)
    - Zhitie prepodobnogo ottsa nashego Ioanna Damaskina i sviatitelia Spiridona Trimifontskogo, booklet, 1962 (Folder 13: 15)